Inventory of the Yonah Alexander papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Yonah Alexander papers
1966-2013
2010C24
Hoover Institution Archives
56 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (22.4 linear feet)
Writings, reports, studies, conference papers, serial issues, journal articles, bulletins, and newsletters relating to domestic and international terrorism, and to the counter-terrorist institutes at the Potomac Institution for Policy Studies, including the Inter-University Center for Policy Studies and the International Center for Terrorism Studies.
Alexander, Yonah
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2010. Increment was added in 2011 and 2013. Finding aid updated through March 2014.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Born on 25 December 1931 in Grodno, Poland, but later emigrated to Mandatory Palestine. Legally changed his name from Alexandrowitz in 1952, and married Penina Segalowitz on December 11, 1956.
Received his Bachelor's in Political Science from Roosevelt University in 1954, his Master's in International Relations from The University of Chicago in 1955 and his PhD in Public Law and Government from Colombia University in 1965. Professor of International Studies at the State University of New York from 1965-1990, where he became Director of the Institute for Studies in International Terrorism from 1976-1992. In 1988 he also became director of Terroristm Studies Program as well as the Group Rights Program at George Washington University.
Alexander Alexander was also made the Co-Director of the Inter-University Center for Legal Studies and Director of the Inter-University Center for Terrorism Studies. He has served as a Senior Fellow at the Potomac Institute for Policy Studies and Director of its International Center for Terrorism Studies. Additionally, Alexander has authored and edited numerous books, journals, and articles on terrorism, lectured at numerous educational institutions and universities, both domestically and internationally, while also receiving numerous grants and research appointments. Alexander has also founded two academic journals: in 1993 he founded the International Journal on Minority and Group Rights, and in 1998 he founded Terrorism: An Electric Journal and Knowledge Base.
Some of his notable works include Usama bin Laden's al-Qaida: Profile of a Terrorist Network (2001), Cyber Terrorism and Information Warfare: Threats and Responses (2001), U.S. Federal Legal Responses to Terrorism (2002), Evolution of U.S. Counterterrorism Policy (2008), New Iranian Leadership: Ahmadinejad, Terrorism, Nuclear Ambition, and the Middle East (2008), and Al-Qaida: Ten Years After 9/11 and Beyond (2012). He has also compiled and edited several volumes of the multi-volume series Terrorism: Documents of International and Local Control.
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, reports, studies, conference papers, serial issues, books, journal articles, bulletins, and newsletters relating to domestic and international terrorism, to the International Center for Terrorism Studies and the Inter-University Center for Terrorism Studies at the Potomac Institute for Policy Studies.
The bulk of the collection consists of drafts, manuscripts, and final publications of works either authored or edited by Yonah Alexander (included in the Writings series), or published by the Potomac Institute (included in the Potomac Institute series). Of note in the Potomac Institute series are the drafts of the Daily Terrorism Weather Reports covering the years 2002-2010 as well as the printed materials series, consisting of rare newsletters and publications regarding terrorism.
Terrorism--Prevention.; Terrorism.
- Biographical File, 1979-2012 (Box 1)
  Series description
  Biographical File, 1979-2012. Includes correspondence, curriculum vitae, press materials, and copies of photographs of Yonah Alexander.
  - Certificates, 1995-2008 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Conferences chaired by Yonah Alexander, 1994-2008 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Copies of photos of Yonah Alexander, 2005-2007 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Curriculum vitae, undated (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Institute for Studies in International Terrorism Program, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Interviews and articles featuring Yonah Alexander, 1984-2012 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Partial list of subjects, 2008 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Planning materials for Oceana Book Series, 2000 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Press materials for books, 1989-2011 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Press promoting Yonah Alexander, undated (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Short biography of Yonah Alexander, 2010 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Super Terrorism Task Force planning materials, 1985-1995 (Box-folder 1: 12)
- Copies of photographs, 2000 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  Scope and Contents note
  Five printed scans of photographs, including one of the Pope, one scan of an ad from the Geo W. King Company, one photo of a child with a gun, one photo of a female dressed mannequin, and one of a baby, both dressed with bomb belts.
- Correspondence, 1979-2008 (Box 1)
  Series Description
  Correspondence to and from Yonah Alexander.
  - George Washington University correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Various correspondents, 1979-2008 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - File titled "Terrorist Files", 1979 (Box-folder 1: 16)
- Writings, 1979-2012 (Boxes 2 - 24)
  Includes journal articles, research notes, manuscripts, galley pages, and drafts of writings authored by Yonah Alexander arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Journal Articles and Research, 1979-2011
    Includes drafts of articles, final articles, notes, and research materials of short works authored by Yonah Alexander.
    - "Current Trends in Terrorism" article draft, 1985 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - Data gathered regarding criminal charges against terrorists, 1995 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - "Democratic Front for the Liberation of Palestine", undated (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - Diagrams and research notes on Iran, circa 2000s (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - Hamas article draft, undated (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - Narco-terrorism proposal outline, undated (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - Nuclear terrorism article draft, undated (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - Periodical articles, 1979-2011 (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - State sponsored terrorism article draft (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - "Terrorism in the Year 2000" Article (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - Terrorist organization diagrams, 2004 (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - Terrorist profiles, 2004 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Aerial Piracy and Aviation Security Manuscript, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 13-16)
  - al-Qa'ida Ten Years After 9/11 and Beyond manuscript, 2012
    - Chapters 1-7, 2012 (Box-folder 2: 17-18)
    - Chapter 8, Appendices 1-3, 2012 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - Appendix 4, Selected Bibliography, 2012 (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - Translation of al-Qa'ida manual, 2012 (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - al-Qaida timeline, 2012 (Box-folder 3: 4-5)
  - Canada's Legal Response to Terrorism manuscript table of contents, acknowledgements, 2010 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Cases and Materials on Terrorism manuscript Chapters 1-16, 1993 (Box-folder 3: 7-10)
  - Cases and Materials on Terrorism manuscript, 1994 (Box-folder 4: 1-3)
  - The Commercials of the E.T.A., 2008 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Counterterrorism Strategies: Successes and Failures of Six Nations manuscript, 2006 (Box-folder 4: 5-9, 5: 1-3)
  - Cyber Warfare book outline, 2001 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Evolution of U.S. Counterterrorism Policy undated manuscript, circa 2007 (Boxes 5-8)
    - Outline, circa 2007 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - Manuscript, circa 2007 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - Outline, circa 2007 (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - Chapter 1, circa 2007 (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - Introduction, outline, selected bibliography, circa 2007 (Box-folder 5: 9)
    - Part I Chapter 1, circa 2007 (Box-folder 5: 10-11)
    - Part I Chapter 2, circa 2007 (Box-folder 5: 12)
    - Part I Chapter 1, 3, circa 2007 (Box-folder 5: 13)
    - Part I Chapter 3-5, circa 2007 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Part I Chapter 2-3, circa 2007 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Part II Chapter 1, circa 2007 (Box-folder 6: 3-5)
    - Part II Chapter 2-3, circa 2007 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - Part II Chapter 4-6, circa 2007 (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - Part II Chapter 7-9, circa 2007 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - Part III Chapter 2, circa 2007 (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - Part III Chapter 3, circa 2007 (Box-folder 6: 10-11)
    - Part III Chapter 4, circa 2007 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Part III Chapter 6, circa 2007 (Box-folder 7: 2-4)
    - Part III Chapter 8, circa 2007 (Box-folder 7: 5-7)
    - Part III Chapter 8, 10A, circa 2007 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - Part III Chapter 9, circa 2007 (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - Part III Chapter 10, circa 2007 (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - Part III Chapter 11, circa 2007 (Box-folder 7: 10-11, 8: 1-3)
  - Evolution of U.S. Counterterrorism Policy draft 2 manuscript, 2007 (Boxes 8-9)
    - Draft 2 Outline, 2007 (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - Draft 2 Introduction, 2007 (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - Draft 2 Chapter 2, 2007 (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - Draft 2 Part I Chapter 3, 2007 (Box-folder 8: 7)
    - Draft 2 Part I Chapter 4, 2007 (Box-folder 8: 8)
    - Draft 2 Part I Chapters 5-7, 2007 (Box-folder 8: 9)
    - Draft 2 Part II Chapter 8, 2007 (Box-folder 8: 10)
    - Draft 2 Part II Chapters 9-11, 2007 (Box-folder 8: 11)
    - Draft 2 Part II Chapters 12-13, 2007 (Box-folder 8: 12)
    - Draft 2 Part II Chapters 14-17, 2007 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - Draft 2 Part III, 2007 (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - Draft 2 Part III Chapter 18, 2007 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - Draft 2 Part III Chapter 19, 2007 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - Draft 2 Part III Chapter 20, 2007 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - Draft 2 Part III Chapter 21, 2007 (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - Draft 2 Part III Chapter 23, 2007 (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - Draft 2 Part III Chapter 24-26, 2007 (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - Draft 2 Part III Chapter 27, 2007 (Box-folder 9: 9)
    - Draft 2 Part III Chapter 28-29, Bibliography, 2007 (Box-folder 9: 10)
    - Draft 2 Indexing documentation, 2007 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Evolution of U.S. Counterterrorism Policy draft 3 manuscript, 2007 (Box-folder 10: 1-9)
    - Draft 3 Contents Volumes I-III, 2007 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - Draft 3 Contents, Introduction, Acknowledgements, Index, 2007 (Box-folder 10: 2)
    - Draft 3 Part I Foreword, Chapters 1-4, 2007 (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - Draft 3 Foreword, Introduction, Chapters 1-2, 2007 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - Draft 3 Chapters 3-4, 2007 (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - Draft 3 Chapters 5-7, 2007 (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Draft 3 Chapters 8-9, 2007 (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - Draft 3 Foreword, Preface, Contents, Chapters 10-11, 2007 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - Draft 3 Chapters 12-16, 2007 (Box-folder 10: 9)
    - Draft 3 Chapters 17-18, 2007 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Draft 3 Chapters 19-20, 2007 (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - Draft 3 Volume III Contents, Chapters 21-22, 2007 (Box-folder 11: 3)
    - Draft 3 Chapters 23-25, 2007 (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - Draft 3 Chapters 26-27, 2007 (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - Draft 3 Notes, 2007 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Evolution of U.S. Counterterrorism Policy research materials, 2008 (Box-folder 11: 7-9)
  - Evolution of U.S. Counterterrorism Policy research materials, 2008 (Box-folder 12: 1-8)
  - International Journal on Minority and Group Rights Volume I No. 1 draft, 1998 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - International Journal on Minority and Group Rights Volume 6 Number 3 draft, 1999 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Legal Aspects of Terrorism: United States Volume I planning material, 2000 (Box-folder 13: 3-4)
  - Legal Aspects of Terrorism: United States Volume II planning material, 2000 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Maritime Terrorism: From Piracy to Strategic Challenges manuscript, 2003 (Box-folder 13: 6-8)
    - Chapters 2-5, 2003 (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - Chapters 6-7, 2003 (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - Chapters 8-9, 2003 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - New Iranian Leadership draft 1 manuscript, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 14: 1-12)
    - Selected Bibliography, 2007 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Preface, 2007 (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - Chapter 1, appendix 1, profiles, 2007 (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Draft 1 Chapter 1, 2007 (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - Draft 1 Chapter 2 (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Draft 1 Chapter 3 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Draft 1 Chapter 3 (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - Hamas and Hizballah, 2007 (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - Hamas and Hizballah (Box-folder 14: 9)
    - Hamas Profile, 2006 (Box-folder 14: 10)
    - Chapter 4 (Box-folder 14: 11)
    - Appendices I-II, Notes (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - New Iranian Leadership draft 2 manuscript, 2007
    - Preface, contents, acknowledgements, 2007 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Chapters 1-5, 2007 (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - Chapters 1-5, 2007 (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - Chapters 1-4, 2007 (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - Chapters 1-2, 2007 (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Chapters 1,5, 2007 (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - Chapters 5-7, 2007 (Box-folder 15: 7)
    - Chapters 5, 2007 (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - Chapters 7, Appendices, Bibliography, 2007 (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - Appendices I-II, list of acronyms, 2007 (Box-folder 15: 10)
    - "Leadership Profiles", 2007 (Box-folder 15: 11)
    - "Iran's Nuclear Ambitions", 2007 (Box-folder 15: 12)
  - New Iranian Leadership research materials, 2006-2008
    - New Iranian Leadership research materials, 2007 (Box-folder 15: 13)
    - Outline, 2008 (Box-folder 16: 1-2)
    - Hamas (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - Selected bibliography, 2008 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - Oceana Terrorism and Law Book Series Volume IV draft, 2000 (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - Oceana Terrorism and Law Book Series draft materials, 2000 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Oceana Terrorism and Law Book Series Volume III Aviation draft, 2000 (Box-folder 17: 3-4)
  - Oceana Terrorism and Law Book Series Volume III-IV draft, 2000 (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - Oceana Terrorism and Law Book Serie s research materials, 2000 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - Palestinian Secular Terrorism bibliography, 2003 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Political Terrorism and Business manuscript, 1979 (Box-folder 18: 2-3)
  - Role of Communications in the Middle East Conflict draft, 2010 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - Terrorism and Homeland Security galley proofs, 2005 (Box-folder 18: 5-6)
  - Terrorism: Documents of International and Local Control, 2002 (Boxes 18-21)
    - Volumes 19-22 Table of Contents, 2002 (Box-folder 18: 7)
    - Volume 33 manuscript pages 1-487, 2002 (Box-folder 19: 1-4)
    - Volume 34 manuscript documents 1-8, 2002 (Box-folder 19: 5-7)
    - Volume 34 Manuscript pages 1-628, 2002 (Box-folder 20: 1-5)
    - Volume 35 manuscript pages 1-697, 2002 (Box-folder 20: 6-7, 21: 1-3)
  - Terror on the High Seas book Volume I-II, 2009 (Box-folder 21: 4-5)
  - Turkey Manuscript, 2007-2008 (Boxes 22-23)
    - Draft Materials, 2007 (Box-folder 22: 1-3)
    - Documents 11-20, Draft Preface, circa 2007 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - Parts 1-3, 2008 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Parts 3-6, 2008 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - Parts 7-9, 2008 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Parts 10-12, 2008 (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Parts 13, 2008 (Box-folder 22: 9)
    - Parts 14, 2008 (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Parts 15, Notes, Bibliography, 2008 (Box-folder 23: 2)
  - Turkey research materials, circa 2007 (Box-folder 23: 3)
  - The U.K.'s Legal Response to Terrorism manuscript, 2002-2003 (Boxes 23-24)
    - Pages 1-254, 2003 (Box-folder 23: 4-5)
    - Pages 1-424, 2002 (Box-folder 23: 6-9)
    - Pages 425-692, 2002 (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
  - Usama bin Laden's al-Qaida: Profile of a Terrorist Network, 2001 (Box-folder 24: 3-5)
    - Manuscript pages 1-51, 2001 (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - Research materials, 2001 (Box-folder 24: 4-5)
  - U.S. Federal Legal Responses to Terrorism manuscript pages 1-276, 2002 (Box-folder 24: 6-7)
- Potomac Institute materials, 1996-2013 (Boxes 25-48)
  Includes drafts and final copies of publications, inter-department proposals, and conference materials from the International Center for Terrorism Studies at the Potomac Institute for Policy Studies.
  - Potomac Institute publications, 2002-2013 (Boxes 25-46)
    Includes drafts, final versions, and research notes of works published by the Potomac Institute for Policy Studies.
    Arrangement Statement
    Series arranged alphabetically by publication title, excluding chronological arrangement of Daily Terrorism Weather Reports subseries.
    - Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, 2002-2010 (Box-folder 25-42)
      Includes drafts of the Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, published by the International Center for Terrorism Studies at the Potomac Institute for Policy Studies covering years 2002-2010.
      - 2002 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, July 12 - December 20 (Box-folder 25: 1-2)
      - 2003 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, Iraq (Box-folder 25: 3)
      - 2003 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, January 1 - June 13 (Box-folder 25: 4-9)
      - 2003 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, June 18 - December 19 (Box-folder 26: 1-8)
      - 2004 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, January 14 - May 25 (Box-folder 27: 1-8)
      - 2004 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, June 1 - October 14 (Box-folder 28: 1-9)
      - 2004 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, October 15 - December 27 (Box-folder 29: 1 - 7)
      - 2005 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, January 5 - April 6 (Box-folder 30: 1 - 8)
      - 2005 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, April 7 - June 23 (Box-folder 31: 1 - 8)
      - 2005 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, June 24 - October 7 (Box-folder 32: 1 - 8)
      - 2005 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, October 8 - December 22 (Box-folder 33: 1 - 8)
      - 2006 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, January 5 - May 31 (Box-folder 34: 1 - 8)
      - 2006 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, June 1 - December 21 (Box-folder 35: 1 - 3)
      - 2007 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, January 4 - February 28 (Box-folder 35: 4 - 9)
      - 2007 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, March 1 - October 3 (Box-folder 36: 1 - 8)
      - 2008 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, Turkey (Box-folder 36: 9)
      - 2008 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, December 18 - December 23 (Box-folder 36: 10)
      - 2008 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, December 24 - December 31 (Box-folder 37: 1)
      - 2009 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, January 7 - April 21 (Box-folder 37: 2-8)
      - 2009 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, April 22 - July 9 (Box-folder 38: 1-8)
      - 2009 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, July 10 - December 31 (Box-folder 39: 1-6)
      - 2010 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, January 3 - January 31 (Box-folder 39: 7)
      - 2010 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, February 12 - June 30 (Box-folder 40: 1-10)
      - 2010 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, July 6 - October 31 (Box-folder 41: 1-8)
      - 2010 Daily Terrorism Weather Reports, November 1 - December 15 (Box-folder 42: 1-3)
    - al-Qaida background materials, 2011 (Box-folder 42: 4)
    - al-Qaida Special Report, 2001 (Box-folder 42: 5)
    - Arab Spring: A Year Later report draft, 2012 (Box-folder 42: 6)
    - Arab Spring: One Year Later report draft, 2012 (Box-folder 42: 7)
    - Best Available Science Fundamental Metrics for Evaluation of Scientific Claims Book, 2010 (Box-folder 43: 1)
    - Biological Terrorism: Political and Legal, 1998 (Box-folder 43: 2)
    - Challenges for Western Security and Defense: Turkey, 1999 (Box-folder 43: 3-4)
      - Versions A and B, 1999 (Box-folder 43: 3)
      - Drafts and Final, 1999 (Box-folder 43: 4)
    - Combating Terrorism (Box-folder 43: 5)
    - Control of Agent Best Systems Transition Study, 2003 (Box-folder 43: 6)
    - Consequences of Terrorism Report, 2011 (Box-folder 43: 7)
    - Counterterrorism Strategies: Cyber Challenges, 2000 (Box-folder 43: 8)
    - Counterterrorism Strategies: Latin American Perspectives, 1999 (Box-folder 43: 9)
    - Counterterrorism Strategies: Legal Perspectives, 2000 (Box-folder 43: 10)
    - Counterterrorism Strategies: Millennial Challenges, 2000 (Box-folder 43: 11)
    - Counterterrorism Strategies: Selected Perspectives, 2000 (Box-folder 43: 12)
    - Counterterrorism Strategies: U.S. Perspectives, 1999 (Box-folder 43: 13)
    - Cyber Terrorism and Information Warfare, 1998 (Box-folder 43: 14)
    - Detention, Prosecution, and Punishment of Terrorists, 2009 (Box-folder 44: 1)
    - Emerging Threats of Biological Terrorism, 1998 (Box-folder 44: 2)
    - Focus Journal, 2004-2012 (Box-folder 44: 3)
    - Fog of War and Law, 2009 (Box-folder 44: 4)
    - Hot Zone '99 Countering Biological Terrorism Final Report, 1999 (Box-folder 44: 5-6)
    - Hot Zone '99 Advanced Technology Needs for Consequences, 1999 (Box-folder 44: 7-8)
    - Hungary-U.S. Strategic Partnership, 2010 (Box-folder 44: 9)
    - Increasing Threat of Contemporary Terrorism, 1998 (Box-folder 44: 10)
    - International Cooperation in Combating Terrorism, 2012 (Box-folder 44: 11)
    - Iran and U.S. Policy, 2010 (Box-folder 44: 12)
    - Iran's Nuclear Program draft, 2011 (Box-folder 44: 13)
    - Legal Perspectives on Counter-Terrorism Strategies of Regional Organizations, 2009 (Box-folder 44: 14)
    - Maghreb and Sahel Terrorism: Addressing the Rising Threat from al-Qaeda and Other Terrorists in North and West/Central Africa, 2010 (Box-folder 45: 1)
    - Maghreb and Sahel Terrorism manuscript, 2010 (Box-folder 45: 2)
    - Middle East Security and the Changing Trans-Atlantic Partnership, 2012 (Box-folder 45: 3)
    - New Emerging Middle East and State-Sponsored Terrorism, 2011 (Box-folder 45: 4)
    - New Middle East: Quo Vadis?, 2011 (Box-folder 45: 5)
    - "New Security Directions" article, 2008 (Box-folder 45: 6)
    - Out of the Box and Into the Future: a National Security Forecast, 2001 (Box-folder 45: 7)
    - Palestinian Terrorism: Secular Group Profiles, 2001 (Box-folder 45: 8)
    - Perspectives on Detention, Prosecution, and Punishment of Terrorists, 2011 (Box-folder 45: 9-11)
      - Table of contents, acknowledgements, contributors, 2011 (Box-folder 45: 9)
      - Manuscript, 2011 (Box-folder 45: 10)
      - Final book, 2011 (Box-folder 45: 11)
    - Romania-U.S. Strategic Partnership: Past Experience and Future Outlook, 2010 (Box-folder 45: 12)
    - Roundtable on Biological Terrorism: Political and Legal Responses, 1998 (Box-folder 45: 13)
    - "Russian Cyber Operations" article authored by David J. Smith, 2012 (Box-folder 45: 14)
    - Seminar papers, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 45: 15)
    - Strategic Response to South Asia's Security Challenges, 2012 (Box-folder 45: 16)
    - SYNESIS Journal Volume 1, 2010 (Box-folder 45: 17)
    - Syria After Assad draft, 2012 (Box-folder 45: 18)
    - Technologically-Based Biodefense book, 2003 (Box-folder 45: 19)
    - Terrorism: An Electronic Journal and Knowledge Base draft and ISSN form, 2012 (Box-folder 46: 1)
    - Terrorism and the Role of Diplomacy, 2009 (Box-folder 46: 2)
    - Terrorism: Current and Future Trends, 1998 (Box-folder 46: 3)
    - Terrorism in North Africa and the Sahel, 2013 (Box-folder 46: 4)
    - Terrorism Report Edition 2, Volume 1, 2009 (Box-folder 46: 5)
    - Terrorism: Review of 2008 and Outlook for 2009 (Box-folder 46: 6)
    - Terrorism: Review of 2010 and Outlook for 2011 (Box-folder 46: 7)
    - Transitioning DARPA Technology report, 2001 (Box-folder 46: 8)